Sanchit Dang

Belmont, Victoria, Australia



sanchitd5@live.com



linkedin.com/in/sanchitd5

Summary

Experienced Full Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the IT industry with programming platforms like Javascript, ReactJS, NodeJS, React Native, and Flutter. Also, have a strong hand in Adobe Creative Cloud Suite. Engineering professional with a Master of Information Technology focused on Cyber Security from Deakin University.

Experience



Senior Full Stack Engineer

Australia Post

Nov 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

- Design & implement software design specifications.
- Perform requirements and code analysis, identification of code metrics, system risk analysis and software reliability analysis.
- Application performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, and automation.
- Create, maintain, and run unit tests for both new and existing code with the target of delivering defectfree code.
- Translate mock-ups and wireframes into functioning front-end code.
- Conduct design and code reviews and collaborate to ensure your own code passes review.
- Work with Product Owners/Scrum Masters to analyse and deliver requirements.
- Collaborate on technical architecture and design.
- Design and develop applications with an eye towards simplicity and reliability.



Senior Full Stack Engineer

OneView Commerce

Nov 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

- Design & implement software design specifications.
- Perform requirements and code analysis, identification of code metrics, system risk analysis and software reliability analysis.
- Application performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, and automation.
- Create, maintain, and run unit tests for both new and existing code with the target of delivering defectfree code.
- Translate mock-ups and wireframes into functioning front-end code.
- Conduct design and code reviews and collaborate to ensure your own code passes review.
- Work with Product Owners/Scrum Masters to analyse and deliver requirements.
- Collaborate on technical architecture and design.
- Design and develop applications with an eye towards simplicity and reliability.



Mobile and Web Application Developer

Deakin University

May 2019 - Nov 2021 (2 years 7 months)

- Create user-friendly web and cross-platform applications using the following languages: JavaScript, React JS, Flutter, React Native, Node JS.
- Lead a multidisciplinary team with backend and web developers to integrate a smooth functioning system.
- Manage project repositories, doing code reviews and helping peer developers.
- Deploy of the applications on Web servers, Google Play Store and Apple App Store.
- Tactically use Agile and SCRUM methodologies to deliver high-quality projects on a timely basis.

Mobile Application Developer

Faktum Bauprodukte GmbH

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020 (4 months)

- Created cross-platform ordering application for the tiling trade deployed on Google Play Store and Apple App Store.
- Maintained overall user experience and design of the project.
- Development of the Dashboard using ReactJS deployed on Amazon AWS EC2.
- Development of the backend using the HAPI framework on Node JS deployed on Amazon AWS EC2.

The application is an innovative ordering tool for the tiling trade. As a Faktum customer, the user can easily order the products the user requires from a comprehensive product catalog tailored to user's specific needs. Users can compile project-related shopping baskets directly from the construction site and at the same time choose delivery options and many other services. A copy of your order will also be sent by e-mail to the address that user-specified for optimum organization.



Software Engineer Intern

Deakin University

Feb 2019 - May 2019 (4 months)

- Maintaining the overall User Experience and Interface around all the applications being developed
- Worked on the frontend for the applications in the company
- Creating and maintaining Wireframes and Prototypes for providing better requirement clarity to fellow developers
- Run Design Thinking sessions to achieve solutions.



Summer Intern

Deakin University

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019 (5 months)



Sales Representative

Vodafone

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019 (1 year 3 months)

- Consulting Customers regarding the Appropriate Plans and phones
- Focused on providing the good Customer Experience
- Tracking a record at KPI's and targets.
- · Solving Customer Queries related to phone and plans.
- Used EFPOS and till for money transactions

· Have a thorough knowledge of using Seibel

Education

Deakin University

Master of Information Technology, Cyber Security 2017 - 2019

□ Chitkara University

Bachelor of Computer Applications, Computer Programming 2014 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



Learning Design Thinking: Lead Change in Your Organization - Lynda.com

Programming Foundations: Fundamentals - Lynda.com

CSS Essential Training 1 - Lynda.com

Flutter and Dart - Udemy

UC-e41fa17f-2a5e-4969-81e8-fbf9f127e6ee

Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect - Associate - Amazon Web Services

(AWS)

MWKN8Y715EBQQXC1

Skills

React.js • Flutter • React Native • Project Management • Mobile Applications • JavaScript • Adobe XD • C (Programming Language) • Microsoft Office • Microsoft PowerPoint